<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://obraunsdorf.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Memory Safety for the Transition from C/C&#43;&#43; to Rust</title>
      <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/safeffi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/safeffi/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Re-writing or porting existing software to a new programming language in a whole can be a costly venture for companies and organizations. Therefore, it might be more feasible to gradually replace C/C++ code by Rust code and perform the language transition step-by-step. Fortunately, Rust has built-in support for interoperability with C using the Foreign Function Interface (FFI). This allows Rust functions to be integrated in C/C++ code bases or vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilient CFI: Compiler-based Attack Origin Tracking with Dynamic Taint Analysis</title>
      <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/recfi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/recfi/</guid>
      <description>Paper https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-08896-4_9
Talk at ICISC 2021 I presented our results in a hybrid conference at ICISC. Here is the pre-recorded video and the slides.
 Slides: to be published Recording: to be published  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nein.</title>
      <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/unsubscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obraunsdorf.dev/unsubscribe/</guid>
      <description>Schönes Wochenende ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olympic Flag Football: Systems, Tactics, and Benefits for the Development of Tackle Football Players and Clubs</title>
      <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/2023-02-24_bcc_olympicflagfootball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obraunsdorf.dev/talks/2023-02-24_bcc_olympicflagfootball/</guid>
      <description>BCC 2023 Team Germany&amp;rsquo;s offensive coordinator, Hauke Bastert, and I presented recent developments in Flag Football&amp;mdash;in Germany and internationally&amp;mdash;and our learnings from the past few seasons regarding how the game&amp;rsquo;s strategies evolved.
We also interviewed many known national and international athletes who both play Flag Football and Tackle Football to answer the question: How does playing both Flag and Tackle at the same time benefit the skill development of athletes?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://obraunsdorf.dev/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://obraunsdorf.dev/research/</guid>
      <description>Research Interests My main field of interest is software security, including secure software design, memory safety, static program analysis and program instrumentation. These interests manifest mainly in work with the LLVM compiler framework and the Rust programming language&amp;lsquo;s compiler. I&amp;rsquo;m driven to create methods to enabele a secure step-by-step transition from unsafe languages like C/C++ to memory-safe languages, primarily Rust.
Since the beginning of my PhD, I have been very attracted to Rust because of its type system, especially with the Ownership &amp;amp; Borrowing concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>